<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<string_table>

	<!--
		FACTION DESCRIPTIONS
	-->

	<string id="st_faction_stalker">
		<text>Loner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_stalker_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]Loners, also known as free stalkers, are generally unaligned with the various groups operating in the Zone. While factions are organized in hierarchies and commonly have designated leaders and goals, free stalkers only work for themselves and work with whoever suits them. The majority of people roaming the Zone belong to this informal group.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_bandit">
		<text>Bandit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_bandit_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]Bandits are an informal faction of outlaws in the Zone, without affiliation to other groups. Its members regard the lands of the Zone as a lawless place to be exploited for personal gain and fulfillment, a place to live out violent delights and take advantage of the unfortunate people crossing their path. Many of its members led a life of crime even before coming to the Zone, now using its insulated state as a way to hide from the law of the outside world.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_dolg">
		<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_dolg_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]Duty is a paramilitary group and a major faction operating in the Zone. Duty's public motive is to protect the outside world from the dangers of the Zone, shield both the world from it and whatever it holds from the world, ultimately working towards its eradication. While Ukrainian military detachments primarily guard the Zone's borders, Duty takes a much more active role inside the Zone, managing expeditions, assembling efforts to control mutant threats, and pushing back against other groups deemed hostile to their goals. They actively maintain a working relationship with the present military force. Some say they themselves are in part funded by governmental agencies.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_freedom">
		<text>Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_freedom_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]Freedom is a semi-organized anarchist group consisting mainly of free stalkers with the common goal of preserving the Zone in its present state and enabling a peaceful co-existence of all who are interested in its wonders. They directly oppose any faction trying to monopolize control over the Zone. Some say, Freedom's leaders have wisely accepted the fact the Zone can not be eradicated and instead be accepted as an extension of the natural world and as a unique opportunity for research and study that should be open to anyone.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_army">
		<text>Military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_army_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]The Military are composed of Ukrainian troops and commissioned officers and serve as the primary force separating the Zone and the outside world. Their mandate is to prevent unauthorized entry and the transport of illicit goods and artifacts. They are well-equipped for their defense role and their hardline approach often leads to a shoot-on-sight policy. Most of their work focusses on guarding the perimeter, though infrequent operations deeper inside the Zone have taken place in the past. Rumours of corruption among their ranks are common, some believing the Zone's supply chains and infrastructure would not be possible if they were fully committed to their apparent mission.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_ecolog">
		<text>Ecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_ecolog_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]Ecologists are another group operating inside the Zone with an official governmental mandate. They consist of researchers, scientists and contracted field assistants who research artifacts and anomalous areas. Their goal is to harness the Zone's inert mysteries, control and utilize them, and potentially develop technological advancements. Ecologists commonly operate with decentralized groups with their own organizational structures. Of all factions, Ecologist members are generally the most neutral. They tend to keep out of faction conflicts and stick to themselves and their pursuit of knowledge and science.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_killer">
		<text>Mercenary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_killer_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]Mercenaries are a loose group of private military contractors (PMCs) working in the Zone for outside clients or benefactors. These operators tend to work independently or in smaller squads and may be hostile towards interference when on an active assignment. Unlike other factions, mercenaries don't share common goals,  or live a communal life with other stalkers. It is rumoured that their members use undisclosed entries and exits to the Zone further north. Many mercenaries were formerly stalkers or stationed military personnel who now offer their services for a price to interested parties.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_monolith">
		<text>Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_monolith_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]The followers of the Monolith are a religious cult that has settled in the deepest reaches of the Zone. The group believes in the elusive power and commandments of the Wish Granter, a strange monolithic artifact rumoured to exist at the heart of the Zone. Not much is known about the origin of its members, though their fanatic and aggressive behavior suggests a sort of advanced brainwashing and after-effects of psy emission exposure. Monolith can notably pass through areas affected by the brain scorcher and are generally ignored by mutated wildlife, making a deeper paranatural bond with the Zone likely.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_csky">
		<text>Clear Sky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_csky_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]Clear Sky are an independent fringe group dedicated to research the mysteries of the Zone. The origins of Clear Sky date back to before the founding of all other factions. A bulk of the group was devastated by the occurrence of the Second Emission and the successive expeditionary effort, leaving only a small number of remnants at the faction's base in the Great Swamps, hidden from the rest of the Zone. Its members maintain good relations with ecologists and military forces.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_renegade">
		<text>Renegade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_renegade_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]Renegades are a ruthless splinter group of rogue stalkers with no leaders or hierarchical structure. Many Renegades are outcasts of other factions, former bandits or free stalkers who have betrayed their group or committed other kinds of transgressions. After the events following the Second Emission and territorial fights around the Great Swamps, Renegades are no longer commonly encountered in the Zone.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_greh">
		<text>Sin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_greh_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]Sin are a hostile cult of psychically affected stalkers who believe in the Zone as a divine place for the redemption of humankind with a goal to allow the Zone to grow and subsume the outside world. Members of Sin often display a number of bodily mutations and have suffered from extensive exposure to the Zone's effects. Due to their appearance and dark green hooded outfits, they are also known as "dark stalkers". A possible affiliation with the Monolith is unknown.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_isg">
		<text>UNISG</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_isg_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]The United Nations International Scientific Group is an organization of special forces unit carrying out missions in secret throughout the Zone. General consensus is that while the Military and Ecologists represent local European interests, UNISG may work under the command of other United Nations member states. Its members operate in small but highly capable teams and are hostile to all interference with a strong motivation to prevent leaks on any information about their activities.
		</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_faction_zombied">
		<text>Zombified</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_zombied_desc">
		<text>%c[ui_gray_2]Zombified stalkers are mindless husks, victims of prolonged psy field exposure or lethal doses of radiation. They are hostile to all living beings and will attack on sight with whatever weaponry they have left. They tend to group up with other creatures of the same fate and sometimes congregate in underground spaces.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--
		HEADERS
	-->

	<string id="st_mm_new_game_inventory">
		<text>INVENTORY</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_loadout">
		<text>LOADOUT</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_name">
		<text>NAME:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_faction_2">
		<text>Faction:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_money">
		<text>MONEY:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_points_left">
		<text>POINTS:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_points_used">
		<text>POINTS USED:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_random_location">
		<text>Random Location</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_mm_new_game_relations">
		<text>FACTION RELATIONS:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_description">
		<text>FACTION DESCRIPTION:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_points">
		<text>Points</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Hint -->
	<string id="st_mm_itm_desc_unknown">
		<text>No available info</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Options -->
	<string id="st_cap_check_warfare">
		<text>Warfare</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_check_drx">
		<text>DoctorX Questlines</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_check_campfire">
		<text>Campfire Saving (DON'T TOUCH)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_check_conditions">
		<text>Agony Mode</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_list_timer">
		<text>Timer Mode</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_check_routes">
		<text>Accessible Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_list_hardcore_lives">
		<text>Ironman Lives</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_list_hardcore_regen">
		<text>Life Granter</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_cap_list_difficulty">
		<text>Gameplay Difficulty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_list_economy">
		<text>Progression Difficulty</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>